pagecloud.com 2018-10-25

# PageCloud - Privacy Policy

##  In General Terms

PageCloud Inc. ("PageCloud" or "we") is committed to maintaining the accuracy, security, and privacy of Personal Information in accordance with applicable legislation. This PageCloud Privacy Policy is a statement of principles and guidelines concerning the protection of the Personal Information of our customers, service providers, and other individuals ("you"). This Privacy Policy’s purpose is to codify this commitment and to comply with applicable privacy laws and associated rules governing how personal information is collected, used and disclosed. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of information we collect and receive, the circumstances in which we collect or receive it, and it explains the policies and procedures we have established for its storage, use and in certain circumstances sharing. Our privacy commitment includes ensuring the accuracy, confidentiality, and security of our users’ personal information and allowing our users to request access to, correction of, and deletion of, their personal information.

Your access to and use of PageCloud’s services is subject to the PageCloud Terms of Service (the “Terms”). Any capitalized terms used but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings provided in the Terms.

##  Consent

BY SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO PAGECLOUD OR ITS SERVICE PROVIDERS AND AGENTS, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE, AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW. Subject to legal and contractual requirements, you may refuse or withdraw your consent to certain of the identified purposes at any time by contacting PageCloud’s Chief Privacy Officer using the contact information provided below. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide you or continue to provide you with certain services or information which may be of value to you. If you provide PageCloud or our service providers and agents with personal information of another individual, you represent that you have all necessary authority and/or have obtained all necessary consents from such person to enable us to collect, use and disclose such personal information for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy.The following are examples of circumstances in which we may collect, use or disclose personal information without users’ knowledge or consent:

a)     when the collection, use or disclosure of personal information is permitted or required by law;

b)     in an emergency that threatens and individual’s life, health or personal security;

c)     when the personal information is available from a public source;

d)     when we require legal advice from a lawyer;

e)     for the purposes of collecting debt;

f)     to protect ourselves from fraud; or

g)    to investigate an anticipated breach of an agreement or a contravention of law.

##  How We Collect Personal Information?

We collect personal information about you from a variety of sources, including:

a)     directly from you, including without limitation, when you use or visit our websites or services, contact us,                request information, register an account, administer your account, or participate in promotions;

b)     Input information or data into any of our Services, or post content on your PageCloud website.

c)     From our business partners; [from our business partners [consider any sources that may provide you                      information about users]];

d)     from third party sources; and 

e)     automatically from devices that you use to connect to our website and apps.

We collect personal information to assist us in providing the Services and adapting and updating them to ensure we meet your needs. The types of Information that PageCloud may collect about you depends on how you use PageCloud’s service. Generally, we collect the following information:

  * account/contact information: when you sign up for the Services and create or register an account, input information or data into any of our Services, post content on your PageCloud website, request information from us, participate in any promotions, contests, surveys, or other marketing events associated with PageCloud, sign up for newsletters, submit opinions or questions to us, contact us for support, or otherwise contact us via email, forms or other communication media, we collect information such as your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, gender;
  * communications with PageCloud;
  * payment information: PageCloud may collect payment information such as payment methods and associated contact information
  * third party services: if you link to or connect with third party services, or otherwise integrate third-party products and services with your PageCloud account, including without limitation Facebook and Google for example, they may send us information, all of which will be controlled by such third party service provider and their relationship with you;
  * usage information: we collect information about your interactions with the Services and the PageCloud application, such as visiting our websites, searches, engagement and location information in certain circumstances;
  * log data: this information includes details about how you use the Services, IP addresses, access times, device information, pages you view before and after using the Services, links to third party applications, and hardware and software information;
  * cookies: our site uses “cookies” which enables us to remember and process your requests on our service, it also enables us to understand and save your preferences. You can disable usage of cookies by adjusting the settings on your internet browser, which may also block cookies for any website you visit; and 
  * other sources: to the extent permitted by applicable law we may receive additional information about you, such as demographic data or fraud detection information and warnings, or other information about you from partner ad networks.

By choosing to create an account using a third-party service, you authorize us to collect information necessary to authenticate your account with the third-party service provider.

Information collected automatically through your use of the Services. As set out above, we collect information about how you use the Services and your actions on the Services, including IP addresses, what software and hardware you use (such as browser types, operating systems, ISPs, platform type, device type, mobile device identifiers such as make and model, mobile carrier) features of PageCloud used, PageCloud screens visited or used and associated dates and time stamps, links you click, whether you open messages sent to your account, and other statistics related to your usage of the PageCloud services. We may also use tools, including third-party tools, to collect analytics data. Some of this information is collected through the use of "cookies" and other tracking technologies, such as web beacons, session replay scripts, and similar technologies ("tracking technologies"). We may also work with third party partners to employ tracking technologies.

If you would like to disable our use of tracking technologies in your account, please contact [privacy@pagecloud.com](mailto:privacy@pagecloud.com). Please note that doing so may cause some PageCloud features to not function properly and could negatively affect your experience with the PageCloud service.

###  Aggregated and anonymized information

We may collect information by aggregating and anonymizing other information. The aggregation and anonymization process prevents the information from being reassociated or identified with any one customer account, user, or individual. We may use aggregated and anonymized information for a variety of statistical and analytical purposes.

In general, PageCloud collects, uses, and discloses Personal Information about our clients and service providers in connection with certain services we make available to you. More specifically, we collect, use, and disclose your Personal Information for the following purposes:

  * to verify and authenticate information. 
  * to register users;
  * to provide the Services and operate the business;
  * to respond to customer requests, concerns and complaints, including customer service requests;
  * to administer accounts;
  * to establish and manage customer relationships and provide notifications to you. This may include the sharing of Personal Information by and between PageCloud personnel and affiliated companies and partnerships for such purposes; 
  * to bill you for PageCloud’s services;
  * to share Personal Information to and from third parties for the purpose of providing information about products and services. Such third parties may include other vendors of services and products;
  * to consider whether PageCloud should establish a commercial relationship with customers, suppliers, and other third parties, including to evaluate credit standing and to match credit bureau or credit reporting agency information;
  * to establish and maintain commercial relationships with clients, suppliers, and other third parties, including to issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments, and to fulfill contractual obligations;
  * to optimize experiences by performing analytics and conducting research;
  * customizing experiences by ranking search results, or showing ads based on user history, preferences and searches;
  * to understand and respond to client, supplier, and other third party needs and preferences, including to contact and communicate with such parties and to conduct surveys, research and evaluations; 
  * to develop, enhance, market, sell or otherwise provide PageCloud products and services;
  * to market, sell or otherwise provide products and services of third parties with whom PageCloud has a commercial relationship;
  * to distribute information to individuals on our mail and e-mail lists, including via third party mailing houses and e-mail service providers;
  * to develop and manage our databases;
  * to develop and manage PageCloud business and operations;
  * to detect and protect PageCloud and other third parties against error, negligence, breach of contract, fraud, theft and other illegal activity, and to audit compliance with PageCloud policies and contractual obligations;
  * to engage in business transactions, including the provision of products and services involving PageCloud;
  * as permitted by, and to comply with, any legal or regulatory requirements or provisions;
  * conducting investigations;
  * resolving disputes and enforcing agreements and policies;
  * for any legitimate business purpose, provided that the information is aggregated and anonymized; and
  * for any other purpose to which you consent.

##  To whom do we disclose your Personal Information?

‍‍From time to time, PageCloud may disclose your Personal Information:

  * internally, within the enterprise;
  * to service providers, including an organization or individual retained by PageCloud to perform functions on its behalf, such as marketing, data processing, and document management and office services;
  * to an organization or individual retained by PageCloud to evaluate your creditworthiness or to collect debts outstanding on an account;
  * to a financial institution, on a confidential basis and solely in connection with the assignment of a right to receive payment, the provision of security or other financing arrangements; or
  * to a person who, in the reasonable judgment of PageCloud, is providing or seeking the information as your agent;
  * to any third party or parties, where you consent to such disclosure or where disclosure is required or permitted by law;
  * with vendors we engage to help us gain insights and analytics into how the Services are used and how they might be improved (for example, we may use third-party data enrichment services to match Customer Information or other personally identifiable information we collect with publicly available database information in order to communicate more effectively with you);
  * with third-party service providers who enable certain features or functionalities of the Services that you’ve requested (for example, connecting a third-party account to your PageCloud website);
  * for any legitimate business purpose, provided that the information is aggregated and anonymized.

We won’t sell your Personal Information without your consent unless PageCloud or a business unit of PageCloud is acquired by or merged with another company and your Personal Information is included in the sale. In this event, we will transfer your Personal Information to that third party with the other business assets being transferred and will notify you by email or by putting a prominent notice on our website before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

We may share user personal information with the third party service providers that we use in the provision of the Services, including but not limited to Google Analytics, each of which will have limited access to your information for the purposes of carrying out tasks on our behalf and each of which have their own rules and privacy policies in respect of the collection, use and disclosure of personal information. We encourage you to review these rules and policies.

##  Where do we store your Personal Information?

Your Personal Information is stored in secured locations and on servers located at the facilities of our service providers.  

##  How do we protect your Personal Information?

To help protect the confidentiality of your Personal Information, PageCloud employs industry standard administrative and technological safeguards to protect your Personal Information. For instance, we operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems.

##  Managing Your Information

You have many choices to access the information we collect about you, and about how we use or disclose that information. This section details many of those choices, including how you can exercise rights with respect to your information (including any personally identifiable information), how you can opt out of the collection and use of certain types of information for certain purposes (such as marketing), and how you can use your browser or third-party tools to disable certain collection methods (such as cookies or tracking technologies).

Content you delete from your PageCloud site (including Content containing personal information) may be retained in archived or backed up copies in order to allow for disaster recovery. For instructions on how to permanently delete Content from your PageCloud account, please contact [ privacy@pagecloud.com](mailto:privacy@pagecloud.com). Please note that permanent deletion of website content will mean that you can never access that data or site again through PageCloud. 

You may access, correct, amend, or delete Customer Information we have about you by logging into your account and navigating to your Account page. If you wish to cancel your account, you may do so through your Account page. If you do, personally identifiable information associated with your account will be deleted as soon as is reasonably practical or as required by applicable law. Please note that we may retain information that is otherwise deleted in anonymized and aggregated form, in archived or backed up copies as required pursuant to records retention obligations, or otherwise as required by law.

We may use some of the information we collect for marketing purposes, including to send you promotional communications about new PageCloud features, products, events, or other opportunities. If you wish to stop receiving these communications or to opt out of use of your information for these purposes please contact [ privacy@pagecloud.com](mailto:privacy@pagecloud.com) to opt out.

##  Privacy and our Website

Cookies \- When an individual visitor accesses the PageCloud website, we may use a browser feature called a ‘cookie' to collect information such as the type of Internet browser and operating system the visitor uses, the domain name of the website from which the visitor came, date and duration of the visit, number of visits, average time spent on our website, pages viewed, and number of cookies accumulated. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that identifies the visitor's browser, but not necessarily the visitor, to our computers each time our website is visited. Unless a visitor specifically informs us (e.g. by registering for an event or sending us correspondence from the website), we will not know who the individual visitors are. In addition to the identified purposes described in our Privacy Policy, we may use this website information and share it with other organizations with whom we have a commercial relationship to measure the use of our website, to improve the functionality and content of the website and to facilitate usage by a visitor. Visitors can reset their browsers either to notify them when they have received a cookie or refuse to accept cookies. However, if a visitor refuses to accept cookies, he or she may not be able to use some of the features available on our website.

Online Communications – In order to provide our website visitors with a service or information, visitors may voluntarily submit Personal Information to us for purposes such as asking a question, obtaining information, reviewing or downloading a publication, participating in a seminar or other event, and participating in contests and surveys. If you are known to PageCloud as a registered user of an online service, we may combine and store Personal Information about your use of our website and the online information you have provided with certain other online and offline information we may have collected.

E-Mail Communications \- Occasionally, we may send marketing or promotional e-mail communications to you with information that may be useful, including information about the services of PageCloud and other third parties with whom we have a relationship. We will include instructions on how to unsubscribe and inform us of preferences if you decide you do not want to receive any future marketing or promotional e-mails from PageCloud.

Links \- Our website may contain links to other websites which are provided as a convenience only. Visitors are advised that other third party websites may have different privacy policies and practices than PageCloud, and PageCloud has no responsibility for such third party websites.

##  Changes to the Privacy Policy

PageCloud reserves the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a change to this Privacy Policy, we will post such changes on our website and make such revised policy and changes available upon request to the PageCloud Chief Privacy Officer. However, PageCloud will obtain the necessary consents required under applicable privacy laws if it seeks to collect, use or disclose your Personal Information for purposes other than those to which consent has been obtained unless otherwise required or permitted by law.‍‍‍

##  Further Information

PageCloud has appointed our General Counsel in our Ottawa office as Chief Privacy Officer to oversee compliance with this Privacy Policy and applicable privacy laws. For information on PageCloud’s privacy practices, please contact [privacy@pagecloud.com](mailto:privacy@pagecloud.com)

‍‍‍‍‍‍Try PageClo‍‍‍ud for FREE today!
